Guide to the Hugh Nissenson Papers, 1942-2013 SPEC.RARE.0138
Ohio State University Libraries Special Collections
- Personal Papers, 1942-2012; Series 3
  - Correspondence, 1950s-2010s; Subseries 3.3
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1990s (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2000s (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2010s (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1980s (Box 24, Folder 8-10)
    - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 24, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 6-12)
    - Correspondence, 1960s-1970s (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 23, Folder 1-5)
    - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 22, Folder 2-10)
    - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1950s (Box 21, Folder 5-8)
  - Datebooks, 1976, 1985-2012; Subseries 3.4
    With the exception of the 1976 calendar, this sub-series contains all of Nissenson's datebooks from 1985 to 2012, all produced by the Paris Ritz-Carlton. It appears that Nissenson tended to use them sporadically throughout his life, but almost never missed having one for a year.
    - Datebooks, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Datebooks, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Datebooks, 1987-1988 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Datebooks, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Datebooks, 1991-1992 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Datebooks, 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Datebooks, 1995-1996 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Datebooks, 1997-1998 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Datebooks, 1999-2000 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Datebooks, 2002-2003 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Datebooks, 2004-2005 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Datebooks, 2006-2007 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Datebooks, 2008-2009 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Datebooks, 2010-2011 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Datebooks, 2012 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera, 1940s, 1961-2001, undated; Subseries 3.5
    - Report Cards, 1940s (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Identification, 1961-1987 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Receipts, 1962-1981 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Business cards, undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Pamphlets/Programs, 1954-2001 (Box 55, Folder 1-2)
  - Family, 1970s-2008; Subseries 3.6
    This sub-series contains two primary sets of materials: drawings done by his daughters in the 1970s and items from his daughter Kate's wedding in 2008.
    - Daughter's Drawings, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Daughter's Drawings, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Daughter's Drawings, 1970s (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Kate's Wedding, 2008 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Journals, 1967-2012; Subseries 3.7
    This sub-series contains bound journals that Nissenson used to jot down thoughts, sketch, write down appointments and phone numbers, and generally get his thoughts onto paper. Nissenson used these extensively through his life from the 1960s to the 2010s. These stand in contrast to the sub-series "journal" which provides a narrative and autobiographical description of Nissenson's life (see associated scope/contents note).
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1981 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Journal, 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Journal, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 1983-1984 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 1985-1991 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Journal, 1986-1987 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Journal, 1991 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Journal, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Journal, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Journal, 1993 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Journal, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 1994 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 1994-1995 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Journal, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Journal, 1995-1996 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 1996 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Journal, 1996-1997 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Journal, 1997-1998 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 1998-2000 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 2001 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Journal, 2001-2002 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Journal, 2002-2003 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 2003 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Journal, 2003-2004 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Journal, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 2004 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 2004-2005 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Journal, 2005-2006 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Journal, 2006 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 2006-2007 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Journal, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Journal, 2008-2012 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1967 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Journals, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Journals, 1973 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1979 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1980 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1982-1983 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1983 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Journals, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Journals, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Journals, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1988 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1988 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1992 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1991-1992 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1992 (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1993 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1993-1997 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1994 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1995 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1995 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1996 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1996-1997 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 1997 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 1997 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 1997-1998 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 1998 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1998 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 1999 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 2001 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 2001 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 2001-2002 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Journals, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 2006 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 2006 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Journals, 2009 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Journals, 2012 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Journals, 2012 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Journals, 2012 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Journals, undated (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Journals, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Journals, undated (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Journal, circa 1975-1979 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Journal, circa 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Journal, circa 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Journal, circa 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Journal, circa 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Journal, 2007 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Journal, 2007-2008 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Journal, circa 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1965-1991, 2001; Subseries 3.8
    - Scrapbook, 1965-1967 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Scrapbook, 1968-1977 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Scrapbook, 1968-1989 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1968-1990 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1976 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1985-1986 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1986-1991 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook, 1988 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook, 2001 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Writings, 1942-1997, 2002, undated; Subseries 3.9
    - Papers, 1942-1997 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 6-7)
    - Anniversary Dinner speech, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Gottlieb (Paul) eulogy, 2002 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Unpublished Works, 1979-2007; Series 4
  The Unpublished Works series contains all creative materials produced by Nissenson that were not able to be verified as published, and thus presumed unpublished. The first portion of this series contains written works, primarily short stories, many of which are undated and untitled. The second portion of this series contains visual artwork that Nissenson produced, primarily for his own enjoyment and not for the intention of publically showing. This series spans Nissenson's life from his early life as a writer, attempting to get short stories published to his later life when he was more frequently sketching and producing visual art.
  - 73 BC, draft, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - The Beast Witin, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - The Birds, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - The Blind, manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Boxing & Death of Mrs. Wheeler, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - By the Light of Darkness, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Cage, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - The Crisis, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Dream Play, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - The Founder's Scandalous Faith, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - The Four, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - How Do You Feel?, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 11-12)
  - The Impossible Dream, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - In the Wilderness, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Japanese Party, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - John Garfield, manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Ka, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - The Letter From London, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - The Living Doll, manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
  - The Pay Off, draft, manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 20-22)
  - The Pond, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - The Rebel, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - The Return, draft/notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - The Sentence of Death, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 28-31)
  - Some Children of Israel, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 32-33)
  - The Succubus, draft and manuscript, undated (Box 17, Folder 34-35)
  - To Salvation by Way of New Haven, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - The Telephone, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - The Twilight of the Gods, draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 37-38)
  - The Twilight of the Gods, manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Untitled, Ben Zachail, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - The War of the World, notes and draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - What the Lieutenant Never Told His Grandchildren, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Within a Budding Grove, drafts/manuscript, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - The Yom Kippur Fish, drafts, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Untitled, draft, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Untitled, draft, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Untitled, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 7-12)
  - Untitled, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 14-21)
  - Untitled, draft, undated (Box 18, Folder 23-29)
  - Untitled, "Miscellaneous", Undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Untitled, progress report, Undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Visual Art, 1979 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - Visual Art, circa 1979 (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - Visual Art, 1979-1986 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Visual Art, 1979-1996 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Visual Art, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - Visual Art, 1981 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - Visual Art, 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Visual Art, 1984 (Box 60, Folder 4, 6)
  - Visual Art, 1984-1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Visual Art, 1981-1993 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Visual Art, 1981-1982 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - Visual Art, circa 1982 (Box 60, Folder 11)
  - Visual Art, 1983-2001 (Box 60, Folder 16)
  - Visual Art, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Visual Art, 1988-2007 (Box 60, Folder 12)
  - Visual Art, 1994-1996 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - Visual Art, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Visual Art, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Visual Art, 1990s, undated (Box 63)
  - Visual Art, undated (Box 60, Folder 13, 15)
  - Visual Art, undated (Oversize folder 1)